Register of the Howard Palfrey Jones papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1939-1972 (Box 50-91)
  - Berlin
    - Reconstruction
  - Berlin Wall, circa 1961
  - Biographical material (Box 51)
    - Babbitt, Marcy, "The Life of a Diplomat," manuscript
    - Biographies
    - Book lists
    - Business
    - Clippings, 1948-1972
    - Family (Box 52)
    - Guest lists, telephone lists, address lists, calling cards
    - Interview with Howard P. Jones, 1949
    - Miscellaneous
    - Notes, notebooks, meetings and conferences
    - Organization membership lists, conference lists, calling cards (Box 53)
    - Receipts
    - Recommendations
    - Richards, Florence, "Able Midwesterner in Southeast Asia," The Diplomat, 1962 October
    - Travel itineraries, authorizations, schedules
    - Trip to Washington, D.C., 1970 March
  - Black, Eugene R.
  - Boothe, Laurence
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Bunche, Ralph
  - Bundy, McGeorge
  - Bundy, William
  - Bunker, Ellsworth
  - Burns, Governor John A.
  - Business and Society
  - Campbell, W. Glenn
  - Capitalism
  - Chandler, George
  - Chiang Ching-kuo
  - Chicago, University, Academy for Policy Study
  - Chile
  - China (Box 54)
    - Education of adults
    - Foreign relations
      - Indonesia
      - United States
    - Language
  - Chinese in Indonesia
  - Christian Science
  - Christian Science Monitor
  - Christian Science Sentinel
  - Cities and towns
    - Asia
    - Wisconsin - Milwaukee
  - Civil service law - New York (State)
  - Cleveland, Harlan
  - Colby Junior College, New London, New Hampshire
  - Collected memoranda, letters, 1948-1971
  - Congresses and conventions
    - Belgrade, 1961
    - Conference of Foreign Ministers, Manila, Philippines, 1963
  - Cottle, Sidney
  - Council on Economic and Cultural Affairs (Box 55)
  - Council on Foreign Relations
  - Couve de Murville, Maurice
  - Davis, Saville
  - Democracy
  - Diplomacy
  - Diplomatic and consular service
  - Dominican Republic
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Durbrow, Elbridge
  - East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii
    - Clippings, news releases, reprints, newsletter, notes
    - Correspondence
    - Grants and grant recipients
    - Office memoranda, miscellaneous
    - Report by Howard P. Jones and Arthur Goodfriend on Asia trip, 1967
  - Economic assistance in southeastern Asia
  - The Economist
  - Education (Box 56)
    - Southeastern Asia
    - Social values
  - Educational research
  - Eisenhower, President Dwight D.
  - Emmerson, John K.
  - Employment (economic theory)
  - Europe
    - Eastern
    - Economic integration
  - Fearey, R. A.
  - Fei, W. H.
  - Felt, Adm. H. D.
  - Food relief, American
  - Foreign Policy Reports
  - Foreign Service Association
  - Foreign Service Institute
  - Frankel, Charles
  - Freeman, Orville
  - Gardner, John W.
  - Gaud, William S.
  - Germany
    - Civil service, 1945
    - Currency question
    - Elections, 1953 September 6
    - Foreign exchange, 1947
    - Miscellaneous
    - Public finance
    - Public relations (Box 57)
    - Refugees, 1949
    - Territory Under Allied Occupation, Bipartite, 1945-1955
      - Control Office
        - Office memoranda
        - Reports
  - Goa
  - Goldberg, Arthur J.
  - Gomulka, Wladyslaw
  - Goodfriend, Arthur
  - Great Britain
    - Control Commission for Germany
    - Foreign relations - Indonesia
  - Hamilton, Thomas H. (Box 58)
  - Harriman, W. Averell
  - Hawaii
    - Department of Planning and Economic Development
    - University
  - Hays, Wayne L.
  - Heller, Walter W.
  - Herter, Christian
  - Higgins, Frank H.
  - Hilsman, Roger
  - Hong Kong
  - Hoover Institution, Stanford, California
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K.
  - Hughes, R. John
  - Hughes, Thomas L.
  - Humanism - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies
  - Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Iceland - History
  - Illinois Research
  - India
  - Indonesia (Box 59)
    - General
    - Abdulgani, H. Roeslan
    - Agriculture
    - Agricultural economics
    - Aidit, Dipa N.
    - Anak Agungi
    - Antara News Bulletin (Box 60)
      - Incomplete, 1967
      - Incomplete, 1969 January
      - Incomplete, 1969 February 1-6
      - Incomplete, miscellaneous copies, 1969 February 7-12
    - Anti-American demonstrations
    - Anti-Communist movements
    - Armed forces (Box 61)
    - Baduj people
    - Bank of China
    - Barito River
    - Bey, Arifin
    - Botanical gardens
    - Budiardjo
    - Caltex-Pacific Oil Company
    - Communism
    - Damar, Satya
    - Darmanto, R. M.
    - Derachman Sarmin
    - Description and travel
    - Dhani
    - Diah, B. M.
    - Djuanda
    - Economic conditions
    - Economic planning
    - Economic relations
    - Education (Box 62)
    - Exports
    - Fishing industry
    - Focus on Indonesia
    - Foreign capital investment
    - Foreign investment law
    - Foreign relations (Box 63)
      - China
      - Korea
      - Malaysia
      - Philippines
      - Southeast Asia
      - United States
    - Foreign trade
    - Galbraith, Francis J.
    - Hamengku Buwono IX, Sultan
    - Hanifah, Abu
    - Hatta, Mohammad (Box 64)
    - Health
      - General
      - Malaria eradication
    - Himpunan Mahasiswa Indonesia (HMI) - Indonesian Association of Students
    - History
      - Japanese occupation, 1942-1945
      - Revolution, 1945-1949
      - 1950-1966
        - Bandung Conference, 1954
        - Pemerintah Revolusioner Republik Indonesia (PRRI) Rebellion, 1958
        - Tri-partite Talks, 1964 (Box 65)
        - West Irian Dispute
        - 1966
    - "Hubungan Sipal dan Militer" (Civil and Military Relations)
    - Hutasoit
    - Ide Anak Agung Gde Agung
    - Independence Day
    - Indonesia
    - Indonesian Economic Review
    - The Indonesian Spectator
    - International Rice Research Institute
    - Java
    - Jones, Howard P., clippings, 1962 October-November
    - Jonkman
    - Jusuf, Mohammed
    - Kesatuan Aksi Mahasiswa Indonesia (KAMI)
    - Khouw Bian Tie
    - Kusumowidagdo, Suwito
    - Labor (Box 66)
    - Language
    - Leimena, Johannas
    - Leimena, Mrs. Prawiradilaga
    - Library development
    - Lubis, Mochtar
    - Lukman, Mohamad H.
    - Lydman, Jack
    - Malik, Adam
    - Maps
    - Miscellaneous
    - Molucca Islands
    - Mysticism
    - Nasution
    - National Academy of Sciences - Workshop on Food, 1968 May
    - National Press Digest
    - Natural resources - oil (Box 67)
    - New Guinea
    - News on Indonesia
    - Newspaper clippings, 1958-1972
    - Newspaper photocopies, New York Times, 1964-1965
    - Njono
    - Njoto
    - Officials and employees, notes by Howard P. Jones
    - Pacific-Indonesia Business Association (Box 68)
    - Pagoejoeban Pasoendan
    - Palar
    - Panglaykin, J.
    - Pare
    - Pauker, Guy J.
    - People's Consultative Congress
    - Political leaders
    - Political parties
      - Murba
      - Partai Komunis Indonesia (PKI)
    - Politics and government
      - Constitution, 1945
      - 1950-1966
      - 1966-
    - Prijono (Box 69)
    - Provinces
    - Rachman, Tunku Abdul
    - Rasad, Raffly
    - Religion
    - Report on Indonesia, incomplete, 1952-1953
    - Republic of Indonesia - Information Office
    - The Revolution Fund
    - Roem, Mohammed
    - Rural development
    - Sadli, Mohammad
    - Sajidiman, General
    - Saleh, Chaerul
    - Salim, Emil
    - Sastroamidjojo, Ali
    - Science and technology
    - Sen, Sudhir
    - Simatupang, General
    - Sjafruddin
    - Sjahrir, Sutan
    - Smith, H. Alexander
    - Social life and customs (Box 70)
    - Soedjatmoko
    - Soemantri
    - Student unrest
    - Subandrio
    - Suharto
    - Sukarno
      - Article by Sukarno, Le Monde, 1964 May
      - Biographical information
      - Clippings, articles, 1958-1968 (Box 71)
      - Ideology
      - Kennedy, John F. - Library, Oral History Interview, Bogor, Indonesia, 1964 August 1
      - Miscellaneous
      - Notes, memoranda about Sukarno
      - Policies
      - Speeches
        - 1955-1962
        - 1963-1966
      - Television broadcast, transcript, "Face the Nation,", 1965 January 31
    - Sukisman, Lt. Col (Box 72)
    - Sulong, Zainal
    - Sumatra
    - Sumitro
    - Sumarno, General
    - Supardjo, General
    - Surachman
    - Tan, T. K.
    - Thajeb, Sjarif
    - Tolbert, Stokes M.
    - United Nations
    - University of California - Airlangga University Affiliation
    - University of California - School of Medicine Project, pictorial report, 1959 (Box 73)
    - University of Kentucky Project, Bogor, 1957-1966
    - Van Mook, Hubertus J.
    - Wirjodiprodjo, General Hartono
    - Wirjopranoto, Sukardjo
    - Yani, Achmad
  - Indonesian-American Society of the United States
  - Indonesian Chinese (Box 74)
  - Indonesian Current Affairs Translation
  - Indonesian newspapers, miscellaneous copies, 1958
  - The Indonesian Students Association in the United States
  - Indonesian Summer Institute
  - L'Institut International de Finance Publiques
  - Institute of Current World Affairs
  - Institute on World Affairs
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (Box 75)
  - International business enterprises - Asia Development Bank
  - International Christian Leadership
  - International development
    - Asia
    - Southeast Asia
  - International economic assistance - Indonesia
  - International economic relations
    - General
    - U.S. - Japan
  - International education
  - International Peace Academy (Box 76)
  - International relations
    - Asian-American
    - Malaysia-Indonesia
  - International security - Japanese-American Seminar
  - International Studies Association
  - International trade - Pacific
  - Japan
    - Communist strategy
    - Economic assistance - Indonesia
    - Economic conditions
    - Religion
    - Taxation (Box 77)
    - Whaling industry
  - Johnson, U. Alexis
  - Johnson, President Lyndon B.
  - Jones, Joseph L.
  - Journal of Social and Political Ideas in Japan
  - Juniata College, Huntingdon, Pennsylvania
  - Kashmir
  - Kennedy, President John F.
    - General
    - Library, Waltham, Massachusetts
  - Kennedy, Robert F. - Visit to Indonesia, 1962
  - Kleinjans, Everett (Box 78)
  - Korea
  - Khrushchev, Nikita S.
  - Lea, Homer - burial
  - "Liberty" (pamphlet)
  - Macapagal, President Diosadado
  - McMurty, R. Gerald
  - McNamara, Robert S.
  - Malaysia
    - Agriculture
    - Clippings, news releases
    - Economic conditions
    - Foreign investment
    - Maphilindo, 1963
    - Miscellaneous
    - Printed material
    - Sarawak
    - Singapore
  - Man - Influence on nature (Box 79)
  - Marcos, President Ferdinand E.
  - Mastick, Seabury
  - Mexico - United States Interparliamentary Conference, 1966
  - Michener, James A.
  - Mikoyan, Anastas
  - Miscellaneous - Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, maps, printed material
  - Mossman, James
  - Municipal government
    - East (Far East)
    - France - "Le Probleme de la Reconstruction en France"
    - Germany
    - Union Internationale Des Villes et Pouvoir Locaux
      (International Union of Local Authorities)
  - National Academy of Sciences
  - National Planning Association
    - General
    - Looking Ahead
  - Natural resources - Japan (Box 80)
  - Near East
  - New York (State)
  - Netherlands
    - Dutch East India Company
    - Luns, Joseph
    - Press summaries
  - Nixon, President Richard M.
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)
  - Nuveen, John
  - Okinawa
  - Organization for European Economic Cooperation
  - Pacific Area Travel Association (PATA)
  - Pant, Aba
  - Parsons, J. Graham
  - Pate, Maurice
  - Pauker, Guy
  - Peace
  - Percy, Senator Charles (Box 81)
  - Petroleum
  - Petroleum products
  - Pham Van Dong
  - Phan Quang Dan
  - Philippine Islands - Foreign relations - Asia
  - Philosophy
    - General
    - Fifth East-West Philosopher's Conference
  - Political parties (United States)
  - Population
  - Prevent World War III, 1949 November-December
  - Propaganda - Anti-American
  - Reischauer, Edwin O.
  - Religion
  - Reuter, Ernst
  - Riddleberger, James W.
  - Robertson, Walter S.
  - Romulo, Carlos P.
  - Rotary Club, Honolulu, Hawaii (Box 82)
  - Rotary Club Convention, Nice, France, 1967 May
  - Rostow, Walt W.
  - Rusk, Dean
  - Russia - newspaper clippings
  - Ryuku Islands
  - Sakharov, Andrei
  - Samoa
  - Schermerhorn, Ir. W.
  - Schulte, Ernst
  - Sharp, Admiral U.S.G
  - Sihanouk
  - Smith, Horace H.
  - South America
  - Southeast Asia
  - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (Box 83)
    - Directory
    - Memoranda
    - Miscellaneous
    - Objectives and operations
    - Reports
    - Seminars
  - Stevenson, Adlai E.
  - Sugar growing - Hawaii
  - Swearingen, Rodger
  - Taiwan
    - General
    - Economic conditions
  - Taxation research (Box 84)
  - Taylor, General Maxwell
  - Technology
  - The Temple of Understanding
  - Thailand
    - Economic conditions
    - Municipal government
  - Townsend, Robert
  - United Nations
  - United States
    - Allied Commission for Reparations, 1945
    - Armed Forces
    - Civil service
    - Department of Agriculture
      - Farm Security Agency
      - Food supply
    - Department of Commerce
    - Department of State (1 of 2)
      - Agency for International Development (AID) - Committee on Institutional Cooperation
    - Department of State (2 of 2) (Box 85)
      - Agency for International Development (AID) - Committee on Institutional Cooperation
    - Reciprocal Trade Agreement Program
    - Department of the Air Force - Air War College
    - Department of the Army - Industrial College of the Armed Forces
    - Department of the Navy - Naval War College
      - General
      - Global Strategy Discussion (Box 86)
    - Department of the Treasury
      - Press service
        - 1947 June-November
        - 1947 December-1948 February
      - Tax Study
    - Economic assistance - Indonesia (Box 87)
    - Economic conditions
    - Embassy Translation Unit Press Review
      - Incomplete, 1967 April-July
      - Incomplete, 1967 September-1969 February (Box 88)
    - European Recovery Program (Box 89)
    - Foreign relations
      - Asia
      - China
      - Indonesia
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1958-1969
      - Russia
    - Foreign economic relations - Indonesia
    - Griffin Mission to Southeast Asia, 1950
    - Information Service, incomplete, 1954-1968
    - International Cooperation Administration (ICA) - Indonesia
    - The National War College (Box 90)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity
    - Office of the Military Government for Germany
      - Office memoranda
      - Reports
    - Technical assistance - Asia
  - United States - Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Exchange
  - Urban renewal
  - Vietnam (Box 91)
  - Vietnam conflict, 1961-1975
    - Clippings, news releases, news commentaries
    - Printed material
    - Postwar planning
  - Volunteers for International Technical Assistance (VITA)
  - War
  - Weller, H. L.
  - Western Concrete Reinforcing Steel Institute, 1969 May
  - Wheelock College, Boston, Massachusetts
  - Wolfe, Bertram D.
  - Woods, George D.
  - World Affairs Forum
  - World Bank
  - World Politics
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - General
    - Supreme Headquarters, Allied Expeditionary Force
  - Yamato, Kei C.
  - Yen Hsi-shan
- Ambassadorial Office File, 1959-1971 (Box 92-93)
  Briefing books, cables, lists, meeting notes, office memoranda, telegrams, accumulated by Howard P. Jones, primarily during his years as Ambassador to Indonesia.
  - Briefing books (Box 92)
  - Cables, 1959-1971
  - Embassy residence employees
  - Foreign Affairs Manual Circular
  - Guest lists, address lists, telephone lists
  - Letter of resignation, draft
  - Meeting notes, miscellaneous notes
  - Office memoranda (Box 93)
  - Telegrams, 1959-1969
- Appointment Books, 1953-1967 (Box 94-97)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1953-1959 (Box 94)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 95)
  - 1962-1963 (Box 96)
  - 1964-1967 (Box 97)
- Phonotapes, 1959-1968 (Box 98)
  13 tapes, arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - American Society of Newspaper Editors, speech by Howard P. Jones, 2 tapes, undated (Box 98)
  - Fourth of July statement by Howard P. Jones, undated
  - Humphrey, Vice-President Hubert H., speech at the Kennedy Theatre, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1966 January 2
  - Interview, Howard P. Jones and Robert Campello, Jr., San Francisco, California, 1968 November 27
  - Interview, Howard P. Jones and Betty Cass, Madison, Wisconsin, 1962 October 21
  - Interview, Congressman Silvio O. Conte, 1959 November 6
  - Signing of D.L.F. Loan, Dr. Subandrio and Howard P. Jones, 2 tapes, undated
  - Signing ceremony at Ministry of Finance, 1959 March 18
  - Signing of loan agreement between United States and Indonesia, 1959 March 29
  - Valley Chapter of the North American Aviation Management Club, speech by Howard P. Jones, Studio City, California, 1965 July 21
- Keysort Card File, 1954-1965 (Box 98-100)
  Collected clippings and notes recorded on Keysort cards, coded by subject, geographical area, and date, to allow quick retrieval of subject matter.
  - Book with lists of subjects and explanation of use of Keysort Card File (Box 98)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1959-1970 (Box 101-103)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some government records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - Pre-2010 release of photocopies of declassified records (Box 101-102)
    The original documents were declassified by the U.S. Department of State and have been integrated into the collection.
  - Pre-2010 release of report with classified material deleted (Box 103)
    - Guy J. Pauker, "The Indonesian Doctrine of Territorial Warfare and Territorial Management (U),", 1963 November (Box-folder 103: 1)
      Prepared for United States Air Force Project Rand (Memorandum RM-3312-PR).
  - 2010 release of records, 1960-1968
    Cables, reports, and other records relating to Indonesia. Available as PDF files.
  - 2011 September release of records, 1959-1970
    - Guy J. Pauker, "The Indonesian Doctrine of Territorial Warfare and Territorial Management (U),", 1963 November (Box-folder 103: 2)
      Declassified copy of report prepared for United States Air Force Project Rand (Memorandum RM-3312-PR).
    - Unclassified cables, memos, reports, and printed matter concerning Indonesia, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 103: 3-4)
      Some are photocopies.
  - 2015 August release of records, 1963-1965, 1978 (Box-folder 103: 5)
    Reports, memoranda, and printed matter about Indonesia and Indonesian-American relations from Jones' time as the American Ambassador to Indonesia.
- Photographs
  - 46 photographs of Howard P. Jones, various individuals, and scenes, 1956, 1966-1970, undated (Folder A)
    3 photographs of Howard P. Jones; 5 photographs of Howard P. Jones and Mrs. Jones; 2 photographs of Mrs. Howard P. Jones; 1 photograph of Howard P. Jones and Mrs. Jones with unidentified woman; 1 photograph of Jones with unidentified woman; Jones and unidentified man at the Pacific Area Travel Association Conference, February, 1968; Jones and Walter Robertson and other participants at Colombo Plan Meeting, Wellington, New Zealand, 1956; 1 photograph of Jones and Prince Paku Alam VIII with daughters, Retno Suskamdani and Retno Widanarni, and sons, Harlo Ambarkusuma and Hario Probokusuma; 1 photograph of Jones and other participants at the Global Strategy Discussion, Naval War College, Newport, Rhode Island, June 1970; 1 photograph of Jones and other participants at Aspen Executive Program, 1966; 1 photograph of Jones and Mrs. Jones with Mr. and Mrs. Bernhard Sitompul; 1 photograph of the American Embassy, Djakarta, Indonesia; 1 photograph of the Ambassador's residence, Djakarta, Indonesia; 15 photographs of wall signs and billboards with Indonesian nationalist propaganda; 1 photograph of Otto Djaya and Jones; 1 photograph of Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Istanto; 1 photograph of Mr. Chu Sunario; 1 photograph of Mr. Derachman; 1 photograph of Komodor Udara Tjilik Piwar; 1 photograph of President Sukarno and Mme. Dewi Sukarno; 1 photograph of President Sukarno at the opening ceremony of Universitas "Lambung Mangkurat;" 1 photograph of Angie Kwik; 1 photograph of Ambassador and Mrs. Apa Pant with two children; 1 photograph of the Hotel Pago Pago International; 1 photograph of Herbet Moller.
  - 6 photographs of concentration camp victims, Germany, World War II (Box B)
  - 22 photographs of Berlin Military Post of the United States High Commissioner of Germany (Folder C)
  - 7 photographs of Jones and Vice Admiral Frederick N. Kivette; 1 photograph of Kivette; 3 photographs of Jones and Mrs. Jones with unidentified people; 1 photograph of Jones with unidentified man; 1 photograph of USS St. Paul (Box D)
  - 18 miscellaneous photographs of acquaintances, unidentified people and scenes (Box E)
  - 2 binders of photographs (Folder fF)
  - 1 binder of photographs (Folder fG)
- January 1982 Increment
  - Personal matters; writings, including class material on military government in Germany (Box 114)
  - Speeches and miscellaneous files (Box 115)
  - Correspondence (Box 116)
  - Personnel files; United States (Box 117)
  - Germany (Box 118-121)
  - Postwar reconstruction in Europe and in Taiwan (Box 122-123)
  - Indonesia (Box 124-127)
  - Nuclear proliferation; Radio Australia broadcasts (Box 127)
  - U.S. government memoranda; conference papers (Box 128)
  - Studies; miscellaneous research files; Refugee Relief Act; printed matter (Box 129)
  - Clippings (Box 130-132)
  - Phonotapes, photographs, memorabilia (Box 133)
  - Card file (Box 134)